A Guide to the Virginia Tech and Local History Mounted Clippings, c. 1870s-1960s
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Miscellaneous, 1886-1959
  - General Notes, M165-M299 (Box 3)
    M 166, 196, 201, 218, 224 may include "Technical Topics" (1931-1941). M 167, 168, 171, 175, 188, 192, 215, 218, 231 may include Demolay Club. M 169 may include Industrial Surveys. M 170a may include Southern Collegian Magazine (1931). M 171 may include The Tin Horn (Co-Ed Yearbook, 1929-1931). M 176 may include VPI Skipper (Student Humor Magazine). M 179a, 180, 181 may include Landscape Design School (Short Course). M 180, 205 may include Mccormick, Cyrus Hall Centennial Celebration (1931). M 186, 225 may include American Country Life Association. M 188, 203 may include Chemistry, Dept. Of. M 189 may include Southern Colonels (Dance Orchestra). M 190 may include Roadside Landscaping. M 191 may include Lutheran Students' Association (Of America). M 195 may include Scorpions Club. M 196, 198, 219 may include Rifle Team. M 199 may include Prohibition Poll. M 203 may include Church Attendance. M 205 may include Lonesome Pine Club, Northern Neck Club, and Richmond Club. M 208 may include Pittsylvania Club. M 212 may include Rappahannock Valley Club and Roanoke Club. M 214, 216, 227 may include Swimming Pool. M 215, 230 may include Baptist Student Convention. M 214, 216, 227 may include Swimming Pool. M 215, 230 may include Baptist Student Convention. M 220 may include Athletic Department (Formerly Athletic Association). M 222, 231, 270 may include Depression & Recovery. M 223 may include Bachelor's Club. M 228, 239 may include Beer Licenses. M 230 may include American Legion. M 230, 231 may include Civil Works Project. M 230, 232, 240, 242, 285 may include Rescue Squad. M 231, 237, 239, 262, 276 may include Buildings - Utilities Building. M 234 may include Omicron Delta Kappa (Leadership Fraternity), Alpha Omicron Circle. M 234, 236, 236a may include Virginia Association Of International Relations. M 237 may include Cancer Research. M 241 may include Buildings - Faculty Center. M 241, 244, 245 may include Virginia Library Association. M 241, 258, 262 may include Federal Emergency Relief Administration. M 245 may include Fire Brigade. M 258, 262 may include Merchant Marine Officers Training School. M 262 may include Reflecting Pool. M 268, 275 may include Birds (Study). M 275 may include Aeronautical Course. M 278 may include Guidon. M 295 may include Evening Classes.
  - General Notes, M300-M421 (Box 4)
    M 323 may include American Institute Of Chemical Engineers. M 338 may include Street Lighting. M 352 may include Southern Conference. M 356 may include Cooking For Boys. M 363, 365 may include Nautical Training School. M 363, 387 may include Virginia Educational Association. M 382 may include Student Identification Cards. M 388 may include Post-Graduate Club. M 390 may include Building Layouts. M 404 may include Cooperatives. M 412, 414 may include League Of Virginia Counties. M 417 may include Quadrangle.
  - General Notes, M422-M554 (Box 5)
    M 433, 434 may include Mining Bureau. M 433, 449, 453, 456, 457, 458, 459, 460, 461, 465, 466, 467, 481, 488, 489, 523 may include World War Ii. M 438, 439, 441 may include Training Plane. M 438, 443, 452, 459, 470, 483, 485 may include Works Progress Administration (Wpa). M 443 may include Association Of College Libraries Of Southwest Virginia. M 452 may include Buildings - Seitz Hall (Agricultural Engineering Building). M 481 may include Keramos and Rankine, William J. M. M 490 may include William & Mary, College Of. M 493 may include Recruiting (Military). M 513, 519 may include Water Shortage. M 520 may include American Institute Of Architects.
  - General Notes, M555-M694 (Box 6)
    M 579, 585 may include Nursery School-VPI. M 641 may include Napoleonana Collection. M 658, 660, 677, 691, 693 may include Sewage Disposal Plant.
  - General Notes, M695-M819 (Box 7)
    M 709 may include Buildings - R.O.T.C Building (Building 364). M 710, 757-760, 763, 771-772 may include Mall. M 723 may include Buildings - Mining Engineering Building. M 726, 727, 734, 735, 745, 746, 746a, 804 may include Buildings - Femoyer Hall, Monteith Hall, and Thomas Hall. M 735, 738, 739, 742, 755, 756, 804, 810 may include Buildings - Smyth Hall (Formerly Known As Natural Science Building). M 737, 741 may include Piedmont Research Laboratory (Charlottesville). M 738 may include Tomato Clubs. M 738, 739, 802, 804, 810 may include Buildings - Agnew Hall. M 738, 739, 804, 810 may include Buildings - Price Hall ("Old Aggie"). M 746 may include Winchester Research Laboratory. M 752, 786, 794, 780, 781, 785 may include Buildings - Library (Old Chapel Building) (Burned). M 755, 756, 757 may include Buildings - Dairy Barn. M 757 may include Bear (Wanders Through Campus). M 758 may include War Memorial Chapel. M 773, 774 may include Radio Station - WUVT. M 785, 802 may include Buildings - Lane Hall. M 785, 804 may include Buildings - Campbell Hall (West Stone Dorm). M 807, 812 may include Buildings - Athletic Plant. M 810 may include Buildings - Hutcheson Hall (Formerly New Agricultural Hall) and Performing Arts & Communications Building (Ymca Building, 1899-1936; Old Military Building, 1937-1966; Student Personnel Building, 1966-1972). M 815 may include Motion Picture Unit At VPI.
  - General Notes, M820-M895 (Box 8)
    M 829 may include Racial & Ethnic Minorities (Campus). M 835-837, 870 may include Buildings - Pamplin Hall (Commerce Hall 2). M 862 may include Buildings - Barns. M 868 no. 8 may include Cornerstone Markers (Old Commerce Hall). M 881 may include Computing Center. M 882, 883 may include Buildings - Swine Center. M 886 may include Agriculture & Life Sciences, College Of - Veterinary Science. M 890 may include Mccormick, Cyrus Hall. M 890, 892 may include Buildings - Norris Hall. M 894, 895 may include Name Change.
- Miscellaneous Individuals, 1893; 1901-1959
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla5a-Mla102 (Box 78)
    Mla 31 may include Colors, V.P.I. (Orange & Maroon). Mla 88 may include "GOBBLERS" (nickname).
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla106-Mla234 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla235-Mla352 (Box 80)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla353-Mla464 (Box 81)
    Mla 367 may include Yells-VPI.
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla463-Mla576 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla577-Mla689 (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla690-Mla805 (Box 84)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla806-Mla920 (Box 85)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, Mla921-Mla993 (Box 86)
- Organizations
  Mo 13, 17z may include Rankine, William J. M. Mo 15, 16 may include Student Government Association. Mo 20z73, 23 may include Sigma Mu Sigma (National College Masonic Service Fraternity).
  - Literary Societies, 1887-1927
    Mo 1 may include Lee Literary Society.
    - Literary Societies, Mo1a-Mo1e1 (Box 89)
      Mo 1a, 1b, 1c, 1c1, 1c2, 1d may include Maury Literary Society.
    - Literary Societies, Mo1e2-Mo1g (Box 90)
  - YMCA & YWCA, 1906-1959
    Mo 2 may include Christian Science Organization.
    - YMCA & YWCA, Mo2a-Mo2z52 (Box 90)
  - Fraternities, 1876-1916
    Mo 3 may include Fraternities & Sororities--Social. Mo 3a may include Kappa Sigma. Mo 3b may include Sigma Alpha. Mo 3b, 3d may include Pi Kappa Alpha (Social Fraternity). Mo 3c may include Alpha Phi. Mo 3c no. 2 may include Beta Theta Pi (Social Fraternity).
    - Fraternities, Mo3a-Mo3c (Box 90)
  - Musical Clubs and Minstrels, 1910-1959
    Mo 4 may include Music Groups and Tech Minstrels.
    - Musical Clubs and Minstrels, Mo4a-Mo4b (Box 90)
    - Musical Clubs and Minstrels, Mo4c-Mo4z14 (Box 91)
      Mo 4m may include Songs Of VPI Incl. Moonlight & VPI, Tech Triumph, Ut Prosim.
  - General notes about organizations
    - General notes about organizations, Mo5a (Box 91)
  - County/City Clubs and Other Clubs, 1917-1959
    Mo 6 may include Apple Club; Black Diamond Club; City, County & Sectional Clubs; Lonesome Pine Club; Lynchburg Club; Northern Neck Club; Peanut Club; Pittsylvania Club; Richmond Club; Roanoke Club; and Shenandoah Valley Club.
    - County/City Clubs and Other Clubs, Mo6a-Mo6z19 (Box 91)
    - County/City Clubs and Other Clubs, Mo6z20-Mo6z38 (Box 92)
  - Dramatic Organizations, 1898-1959
    Mo 7 may include Tech Players and Thespian Club.
    - Dramatic Organizations, Mo7a-Mo7z19 (Box 92)
  - Virginia Polytech Society, 1901-1902
    Mo 8 may include Virgnia Polytechnic Societies.
    - Virginia Polytech Society, Mo8a (Box 92)
  - Student Publications, 1896-1959
    - Student Publications, Mo9a-Mo9w (Box 92)
  - Dancing Clubs, 1915-1959
    - Dancing Clubs, Mo10a-Mo10f (Box 92)
    - Dancing Clubs, Mo10g-Mo10z58 (Box 93)
  - Virginia Tech Staff, 1917; 1921-1922; 1924; 1926
    Mo 11 may include Student Publications.
    - Virginia Tech Staff, Mo11a-Mo11b (Box 93)
  - Planters Club, 1917-1918; 1920-1921
    - Planters Club, Mo12a (Box 93)
  - Gold Band Club, 1917-1918
    - Gold Band Club, Mo13a (Box 93)
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1910-1959
    - Cosmopolitan Club, Mo14a-Mo14f (Box 93)
  - Civilian Students, 1938-1959
    - Civilian Students, Mo15a-Mo15k (Box 93)
  - Corps of Cadets, 1895-1959
    Mo 16 may include Honor System.
    - Corps of Cadets, Mo16a-Mo16g (Box 93)
    - Corps of Cadets, Mo16h-Mo16z25 (Box 94)
      Mo 16m, 16r may include Highty-Tighties. Mo 16p may include Kohler Trophy. Mo 16s may include Company B, Corps Of Cadets.
  - Alumni Association, 1900-1959
    Mo 17z, 31-33, 55, 56, 57, 62, 65, 66, 68, 71, 72 may include War Memorial Chapel.
    - Alumni Association, Mo17a-Mo17z37 (Box 94)
      Mo 17g, 17m, 17L may include Buildings - War Memorial Gymnasium. Mo 17h, 17g may include Buildings - Alumni Building. Mo 17s3, 17s5, 17s7 may include Buildings - Miles Stadium, 1926-1964. Mo 17t may include V.P.I. Alumnus. Mo 17z29 may include Campus Development Plan. Mo 17z31 may include Victory Reunion (1946).
    - Alumni Association, Mo17z38-Mo17z106 (Box 95)
      Mo 17z101 may include Carillon.
  - Radio Club, 1920-1921
    - Radio Club, Mo18 (Box 95)
  - Episcopal Club, 1920-1922; 1926
    - Episcopal Club, Mo19 (Box 95)
  - Honor Societies and Academic Honors, 1920-1959
    Mo 20 may include Fraternities--Honorary. Mo 20c, 20f, 20t, 20v, 20w, 20x, 20z, 20z12, 20z40, 20z76, 20z96 may include Sigma Xi (Honorary Faculty Research Society). Mo 20g, 20o, 20w, 20y, 20z, 20z40 may include Pi Delta Epsilon (Journalism Honorary). Mo 20j, 20m, 20o, 20t, 20w, 20x, 20z, 20zl, 20z3, 20z5, 20z95, 20z19, 20z94 may include Omicron Delta Kappa (Leadership Fraternity), Alpha Omicron Circle. Mo 20q, 20s, 20z5, 20z71 may include Alpha Kappa Psi (Professional Business Fraternity). Mo 20z22, 20z23, 20z32, 20z9, 20z70 may include Gregory Guard.
    - Honor Societies and Academic Honors, Mo20a-Mo20z22 (Box 95)
      Mo 20, 20d, 20g2, 20h, 20p, 20r, 20w, 20y, 20zl, 20z2, 20z5, 20z6 may include Phi Kappa Phi (Scholarship Honorary). Mo 20d, 20e, 20f, 20m, 20s may include Alpha Zeta (National Agriculture Society). Mo 20e may include Scorpions Club. Mo 20f, 20g may include Beta Tau Epsilon (Engineering). Mo 20f, 20p, 20z, 20zl, 20z3 may include Phi Lambda Upsilon (Chemistry Honorary). Mo 20g, 20h, 20j, 20p, 20q, 20r, 20u, 20x, 20z, 20z2, 20z11 may include Tau Beta Pi (Engineering Honorary). Mo 20g2 may include Theta Epsilon Theta (Research Honorary Society). Mo 20h may include Phi Gamma Nu. Mo 20h, 20w, 20z2, 20z6, 20z7 may include Sigma Delta Psi (Athletic Honorary). Mo 20m, 20n, 20t, 20z, 20z3, 20z6, 20z8 may include Scabbard & Blade (Honorary Military Society). Mo 20w, 20x, 20z1, 20z3 may include Pi Tau Sigma (National Honorary, Mechanical Engineering). Mo 20w, 20z, 20z1 may include Eta Kappa Nu (Ee Honorary). Mo 20z may include Keramos. Mo 20z, z2, z3 may include Chi Epsilon (Civil Engineering Honorary). Mo 20z1 may include Alpha Sigma Mu (Metallurgical Engineering Fraternity).
    - Honor Societies and Academica Honors, Mo20z23-Mo20z100 (Box 96)
      Mo 20z28, 20z29 may include Sigma Pi Sigma. Mo 20z27 may include Phi Sigma Society (Biological Sciences Honorary). Mo 20z48 may include Pi Omega Pi (Business Education Honorary). Mo 20z60 may include Alpha Phi Omega (National Service Fraternity).
  - Disabled Veterans, 1921-1922
    - Disabled veterans, Mo21 (Box 96)
  - Agricultural Clubs, 1925-1959
    Mo 22 may include American Society Of Agricultural Engineers and Four-H Alumni Club. Mo 22b, 22c, 22d, 22e, 22g may include Agronomy Club.
    - Agriculture Clubs, Mo22a-Mo22p (Box 96)
  - Masonic Club, 1925-1959
    - Masonic Club, Mo23 (Box 96)
  - Senior Privates
    - Senior Privates, Mo24 (Box 96)
      Mo 24 may include "Skippers".
  - Hoof and Horn Club, 1921-1926
    - Hoof and Horn Club, Mo25-Mo25a (Box 96)
  - Science Club, 1922-1959
    - Science Club, Mo26a-Mo26k (Box 97)
  - Dairy Club, 1925-1927
    Mo27 may include Dairy Science Club (American Dairy Science Association).
    - Dairy Club, Mo27 (Box 27)
  - Rifle Club, 1925-1926; 1931-1942; 1949-1959
    - Rifle Club, Mo28a-Mo28h (Box 97)
  - Block and Bridle Club, 1937-1959
    - Block and Bridle Club, Mo29 1937(1) - Mo29 1959 (Box 97)
  - Cave Club, 1943-1959
    - Cave Club, Mo30a-Mo30F (Box 97)
  - Physics Club, 1948-1959
    - Physics Club, Mo31a (Box 97)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1949-1959
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, Mo32a-Mo32b (Box 97)
  - Chemistry Club, 1949-1959
    Mo 33 may include Chemical Club.
    - Chemistry Club, Mo33a (Box 97)
  - Industrial Arts Educations, 1949-1959
    Mo 34 may include Industrial Arts Education Club.
    - Industrial Arts Educations, Mo34 (Box 97)
  - Church Organizations, 1949-1959
    Mo 35 may include Baptist Student Union, Religious Activities, and Wesley Foundation.
    - Church Organizations, Mo35a-Mo35f (Box 97)
  - Young Democrats Club, 1949-1959
    - Young Democrats Club, Mo36 (Box 97)
  - Association for the Advancement of Engineering, 1949-1959
    Mo 37 may include Engineers and Engineering Exposition.
    - Association for the Advancement of Engineering, Mo37a- Mo27k (Box 97)
  - American Institute of Chemical Engineers, 1950-1959
    - American Institute of Chemical Engineers, Mo38 (Box 97)
  - Business Club, 1950-1959
    - Business Club, Mo39a (Box 97)
  - American Society for Metals, 1949-1959
    - American Society for Metals, Mo40 (Box 97)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1951-1959
    - American Association of University Professors, Mo41a-Mo41e (Box 97)
  - Naval Research Unit, 1951-1959
    Mo 42 may include Blacksburg Naval Reserve Research Unit.
    - Naval Research Unit, Mo42a (Box 97)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), 1950-1959 (Box 97)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Mo43a-Mo41e (Box 97)
  - Virginia Society of Professional Engineers, 1950-1959
    - Virginia Society of Professional Engineers, Mo44a-Mo44d (Box 97)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1951-1959
    - American Institute of Architects, Mo45a (Box 97)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1951-1959
    - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, Mo45a (Box 97)
  - Ivy Club, 1952-1959
    - Ivy Club, Mo47a (Box 97)
  - Biology-Science Club, 1953-1959
    - Biology-Science Club, Mo48a (Box 97)
  - Circle K Club
    Mo 49 may include Circle K (Student Organizatons - Service).
    - Circle K Club, MO49-Mo49a (Box 97)
  - Apollo Club
    Mo 50 may include Apollo Club (Weightlifting Club, 1954).
    - Apollo Club, Mo50 (Box 97)
  - Associated General Contractors of American
    - Associated General Contractors of American, Mo51 (Box 97)
  - Institute of Aeronautical Sciences
    - Institute of Aeronautical Sciences, Mo52a-Mo52b (Box 97)
      Mo 52 may include Aeronautical Clubs - American Institute Of Aeronautics; American Institute Aeronautical Science; American Institute Of Aeronautics & Astronautics.
  - Cooperative Engineering Society
    - Cooperative Engineering Society, Mo53 (Box 97)
  - American Institute of Mining Engineering
    Mo 54 may include Burkhart Mining Society.
    - American Institute of Mining Engineering, Mo54 (Box 97)
  - Agricultural Exposition
    - Agricultural Exposition, Mo55a-Mo55w (Box 97)
  - Association of Married Students
    - Association of Married Students, Mo56a-Mo56i (Box 97)
  - Dormitory Cubs
    - Dormitory Cubs, Mo57a-Mo57b (Box 97)
  - Chess Club, 1958
    - Chess Club, Mo59 (Box 97)
  - Holden Society
    Mo 60 may include Holden Society (Student Geological Organization).
    - Holden Society, Mo60a (Box 97)
  - Amateur Radio Club
    Mo 61 may include Amateur Radio Association.
    - Amateur Radio Club, Mo61a (Box 97)
  - Judo Club
    - Judo Club, MO62a (Box 97)
  - Young Republicans
    - Young Republicans, Mo63a (Box 97)
  - Chinese Club
    Mo 64 may include Chinese Student Association.
    - Chinese Club, Mo64a (Box 97)
  - Distributive Educations Club
    Mo 65 may include Distributive Education, Curriculum In.
    - Distributive Educations Club, Mo65 (Box 97)
  - Association of the U.S. Army
    - Association of the U.S. Army, Mo66 (Box 97)
  - Virginia Education Associations, Mo67
    Mo 67 may include Virginia Educational Association.
    - Virginia Education Associations, Mo67 (Box 97)
- Presidents, 1906-1959
  - Presidents, Mp1-Mp112 (Box 98)
    Mp 7 may include Rison Bill. Mp 54 may include Buildings - Burruss Hall.
  - Presidents, Mp113-Mp164 (Box 99)
    Mp 164 may include Name Change.
- Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, 1945-1959
  Mra may include Radford University.
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra1-Mra27 (Box 99)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra28-Mra169 (Box 100)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra170-Mra294 (Box 101)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra295-Mra405 (Box 102)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra406-Mra517 (Box 103)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra518-Mra629 (Box 104)
  - Radford College, Women's Division of VPI, Mra630-Mra671 (Box 105)
- Radio Broadcasting, 1930-1959
  - Radio Broadcasting, Mr0-51 (Box 99)
- Related Agencies, 1949-1959
  - Related Agencies, Mre1-Mre16 (Box 105)
- Student Troubles, 1904-1959
  Mst may include Cadet Scandal and Student Unrest / Troubles / Protests.
  - Student Troubles, Mst1-Mst49 (Box 105)
- Southwest Virginia, 1947-1959
  - Southwest Virginia, Msw0-Msw144 (Box 106)
  - Southwest Virginia, Msw145-Msw252a (Box 107)
  - Southwest Virginia, Msw253-Msw270 (Box 108)
- University Athletics, 1892-1959
  - Baseball, 1895-1959
    AB may include Athletics - Track & Field.
    - Baseball, AB1895-AB1930f (Box 112)
    - Baseball, AB1930g-AB1952b (Box 113)
    - Baseball, AB1952c-AB1959e (Box 114)
  - Basketball, 1910-1959
    ABB may include Athletics - Wrestling.
    - Basketball, ABb1910a-ABb1922c (Box 114)
    - Basketball, ABb1922d-ABb1933c (Box 115)
    - Basketball, ABb1933c-ABb1947p (Box 116)
    - Basketball, ABb1947p-ABb1952m (Box 117)
    - Basketball, ABb1952n-ABb1958c (Box 118)
    - Basketball, ABb1958L-ABb1959z6 (Box 119)
  - Boxing, 1926-1946
    - Boxing, ABo1927-ABo1943e (Box 119)
  - Football, 1892-1959
    AF may include Scrub Football Team. AF 1914c may include Songs Of VPI Incl. Moonlight & VPI, Tech Triumph, Ut Prosim. AF 1919s may include Silent Drill Company. AF 1922L may include Maury Literary Society. AF 1923z3 may include Monogram Club and Buildings - Field House (1914) (Burned). AF 1922z11 may include Dope Book (VPI - Vmi History). AF 1924 may include Athletic Department (Formerly Athletic Association). AF 1955 may include Sword (Ceremonial; VPI-VMI Game). AF 1959z10 may include Television (1959 Homecoming Game - A "First").
    - Football, AF1892-AF1915b (Box 119)
    - Football, AF1915c-AF1921d (Box 120)
    - Football, AF1921e-AF1922z28 (Box 121)
    - Football, AF1922z29-AF1924z (Box 122)
    - Football, AF1924z1-AF1926e (Box 123)
    - Football, AF1926d-AF1928(29) (Box 124)
    - Football, AF1928(30)-AF1930(53) (Box 125)
    - Football, AF1930(54)-AF1933(3) (Box 126)
    - Football, AF1933(4)-AF1936(2) (Box 127)
    - Football, AF1936(3)-AF1938F (Box 128)
    - Football, AF1938g-AF1940g1 (Box 129)
    - Football, AF1940h-AF1942z10 (Box 130)
    - Football, AF1942z11-AF1947g (Box 131)
    - Football, AF1947h-AF1948z37 (Box 132)
    - Football, AF1948z38-AF1950z23 (Box 133)
    - Football, AF1950z24-AF1951z71 (Box 134)
    - Football, AF1951z72g-AF1953z14 (Box 135)
    - Football, AF1953z15-AF1954s (Box 136)
    - Football, AF1954t-AF1955i (Box 137)
    - Football, AF1955j-AF1955z88 (Box 138)
    - Football, AF1955ze9-AF1956z85 (Box 139)
    - Football, AF1956z86-AF1957z58 (Box 140)
    - Football, AF1957z59-AF1958z59 (Box 141)
    - Football, AF1958z60-AF1959z63 (Box 142)
  - General Athletics, 1933-1959
    AG may include Athletics - Intra-Murals; Athletics - Women'S Sports; Athletics, Miscellaneous (Including "Minor", Unlisted Sports); and Miscellaneous Sports.
    AG 1, 5 may include Athletic Department (Formerly Athletic Association). AG 5, 6 may include Southern Conference. AG 5, 6 may include Southern Intercollegiate Athletic Association. AG 11 may include Buildings - Miles Stadium, 1926-1964.
    - General Athletics, AG1-AG8 (Box 142)
    - General Athletics, AG9-AG138 (Box 143)
    - General Athletics, AG139-AG255 (Box 144)
    - General Athletics, AG256-AG279 (Box 145)
  - Golf, 1933-1959
    - Golf, AGo1-AGo19 (Box 145)
  - Lacrosse, 1950-1952
    - Lacrosse, AL1-AL2 (Box 145)
  - Monogram Club, 1930; 1947-1959
    - Monogram Club, AM1-AM8 (Box 145)
  - Swimming, 1934-1959
    - Swimming, As1934(1)-As43 (Box 145)
  - Tennis, 1910-1959
    - Tennis, ATe1910-ATe1959 (Box 147)
  - Track, 1896-1959
    AT may include Athletics - Track & Field. AT 1900, 1903, 1920c may include Field Day.
    - Track, AT1900-AT1922a (Box 145)
    - Track, AT1922b-AT1951e (Box 146)
    - Track, AT1951f-1959a (Box 147)
  - Wrestling, 1921-1959
    - Wrestling, Aw1921-Aw1959c (Box 147)
- University Club, 1929-1959
  Mu may include Buildings - University Club Building (Residence).
  - Universtiy Club, Mu1-Mu17 (Box 108)
- Veterans at VPI
  - Veterans at VPI, Mv1-Mv10 (Box 108)
- Wildlife Conservation, 1937-1959
  - Wildlife Conservation, Mw1-Mw66 (Box 108)
    MW 14, 23, 34, 27, 37, 53 may include Lakes & Ponds.
- World War I, 1917-1919
  W la, 7a, 7c may include American Red Cross.
  - General Notes, W1a-W1g (Box 109)
  - Casualties(Dead and Wounded), W2ca.d1- W2ca.w2 (Box 109)
  - Commissions and Appointments, W2co1-W2co2 (Box 109)
  - Honors, W2h1-W2h4 (Box 109)
  - Inventions, W2i1 (Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, W2m1-W2m17 (Box 109)
  - Promotions, W2p1-W2p2 (Box 109)
  - Special Work, W2s1-W2s2 (Box 109)
  - Letters From VPI men In Service, W3a- W3g (Box 109)
  - ROTC, W4 (Box 109)
  - Students' Army Training Corps, W5a-W5c (Box 109)
  - Training Detachment at VPI, W6a-W6b (Box 109)
  - Blacksburg Activities in the War, W7a-W7b (Box 109)
- World War II, 1942-1945
  - General Notes, W10a1-W10a45 (Box 109)
  - General Notes, W10a46-W10a50 (Box 110)
  - Army Specialized Training Unit, W10as1-W10as11 (Box 110)
  - Casualties, W10ca1-W10ca38 (Box 110)
  - Commissions, Promotions, etc., W10co1-W10co91 (Box 110)
  - Letters from VPI Men in Service, W10L1-W10L11 (Box 111)
  - Miscellaneous Individuals, W10m1-W10m69 (Box 111)
  - ROTC, W10r1-W10r2 (Box 111)
  - Blacksburg Activities/General Notes, W11a1-a32 (Box 111)
  - Civilian Defense-Blacksburg/VPI, W11c1-W11c12 (Box 111)